Shay **Kalyan**



Auckland, New Zealand



+64 27 727 6866



shaykalyan@outlook.com



github.com/xShay

Objective

Software Engineer in Development

Profile

Currently I am an undergraduate student at the University of Auckland, undertaking a Bachelor of Engineering specialising in Software Engineering. My passion in technology has placed me in the position I am in today, pursuing the rapidly growing field of Computer Science and Software. I look forward to contributing to the industry and aid in the evolution of our day to day life.

Education

Bachelor of Engineering (Honours), Software Engineering

2012 - 2016

The University of Auckland

CGPA: **8.7** / 9.0.

National Certificate of Educational Achievement (NCEA)

2009 - 2011

Otumoetai College Level 3 with Excellence.

Awards and Certificates

Dean's Honours List

2012, 2013, 2014

University of Auckland

Awarded to the top 5% of Software Engineering students in the academic year.

First in Course Awards

University of Auckland

- SOFTENG 370: Operating Systems.
- SOFTENG 325: Software Architecture.
- SOFTENG 306: Software Engineering Design 2.
- COMPSCI 314: Modern Data Communications.
- SOFTENG 206: Software Engineering Design 1.
- ENGGEN 131: Introduction to Engineering Computation and Software Development.

Recent Projects

Pebble Watchface: Trace

Personal Project

Technologies: C Language, Javascript, jQuery Mobile, Pebble SDK 2.0.

- Designed and created a minimalist watchface for the Pebble smartwatch, deployed via the Appstore.
- Over 1,700 unique users of the application.

Android Application: Contacts Now

University Project – Individual

Technologies: Java, SQLite, Android SDK.

- Designed and developed a contact management application for the Android platform.
- Implemented an interactive contact card with additional functionality such as navigating to an address.

Employment

Microsoft

Dec 2014 - Feb 2015

Software Engineering Intern

- Implemented support for dynamic virtual machine allocation in a test orchestration system using C#, XML, Visual Studio, and Perforce version control.
- Coordinated with internal teams to elicit requirements and validate the feature specification.

Sapphire Solutions Limited

Dec 2013 - Feb 2014

Software Development Intern

- Redesigned, constructed, and deployed the company's website using modern HTML5 and CSS3.
- Increased web presence in competitive online search by applying Search Engine Optimisation (SEO).
- Created software tools using Windows Forms and C# for internal and external use to assist the operations of the business.
- Prepared client computers for off-site installation.

Target Road Tyres

Jan 2012 - Feb 2013

Administrator / Developer

- Involved in creating a 10 page website to allow the company to showcase thier products and services.
- Applied Search Engine Optimisation (SEO) techniques to increase web reputation.
- Tasked with administrative responsibilities including managing stock and providing tailored solutions for customers.

Volunteer Work

Software Engineering Students Association

2015

Part IV Representative

- Assisted in organising and promoting events hosted by the student led association.
- Provided a friendly and informative communication channel for students to elevate any concerns and provide feedback relating to courses or the university in general.

Peer Support Programme

2011

Student Mentor

- Participated in one-on-one interaction with first year college students to provide mentorship.
- Helped peers adjust to college life by listening to and resolving any academic or social issues they were experiencing.

Skills

Languages

Intermediate

Java, C#.

Basic

C, C++, Python, HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Javascript.

Concepts

• OOP, Databases, Software Version Control.

Systems

- Windows XP, 7, 8.
- Mac OS X 10.10.
- Linux.

Academic Transcript

Available on request.